<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nes on mtbkapp</title>
    <link>https://mtbkapp.github.io/tags/nes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nes on mtbkapp</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 10:01:23 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mtbkapp.github.io/tags/nes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nerdy Nights Week 4</title>
      <link>https://mtbkapp.github.io/posts/nes_6502_part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 10:01:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mtbkapp.github.io/posts/nes_6502_part4/</guid>
      <description>Today I learned about color palettes and sprites. I also learned about a general strategy for updating graphics. The strategy appears to keep sprite data from $0200 to $02ff. Then on NMI update data to set the tile, position, and several other attributes of sprites that need to change. Then setup a DMA transfer of this memory block to the PPU&amp;rsquo;s sprite memory.
I was able to edit the demo code to have the tile and positions of a couple of sprites change on every NMI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nerdy Nights Week 2 &amp; 3</title>
      <link>https://mtbkapp.github.io/posts/nes_6502_part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 10:03:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mtbkapp.github.io/posts/nes_6502_part3/</guid>
      <description>I read the Nerdy Nights weeks 2 &amp;amp; 3 tutorials. I learned a lot more about the NES Architecture, memory, and how the 6502 processor fits into everything.
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why I am surprised by this but it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to me that sending commands to the PPU (picture processing unit) is just writing data to specific memory locations. For some reason I assumed that interfacing with things outside the CPU would be via some specific instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial NES / 6502 Dev Machine Setup</title>
      <link>https://mtbkapp.github.io/posts/6502_dev_machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 14:19:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mtbkapp.github.io/posts/6502_dev_machine/</guid>
      <description>I looked for lists online of tools I&amp;rsquo;ll need to build my Moon Lander game and found the following from FRITZVD. Below is what I&amp;rsquo;ve got setup so far:
 VirtualBox VM w/ the minimal install of Ubuntu Mate (Mate is lightweight and runs well in a VM) Default gVim from apt My Vim setup from my kapp-vim repo The NESASM assembler, built from source. Gimp for making graphics. Although I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be just using white and black for the initial version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bit of 6502 Assembly</title>
      <link>https://mtbkapp.github.io/posts/first_6502/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 14:19:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mtbkapp.github.io/posts/first_6502/content/</guid>
      <description>For some time I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about how fun it would be to build a copy of an old Moon Landing game. I recently discovered that there are tools for writing NES roms from 6502 assembly, C, and JavaScript. I&amp;rsquo;ve got an emulator running on a Raspberry Pi 2 with a SNES controller. I think it would be super fun to build and play a homemade game on it.
To that end I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through Nick Morgan&amp;rsquo;s Easy 6502 Tutorial and it was a lot of fun.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>